Patrick Alcindor

Phone: (646) 787-6436 Email: p.edward.alcindor@gmail.com | GitHub: https://github.com/codystarnyc | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrick-a-a99380147/ | Portfolio: www.PatrickAlcindor.com

OBJECTIVES

A creative, engaging, full stack developer with a passion for front-end development and UI Design. Specializes in customer satisfaction through teamwork and maintains a commitment to exceed expectations. Actively pursuing opportunities to provide programming skills, leadership ability, and enthusiasm to a fast-paced environment as a fullstack developer.

-SKILLS

Programming Languages and Frameworks

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Sinatra, Ruby on Rails, JAVA, Spring, AJAX, ¡Query, ReactJS, Node.JS, SASS, Bootstrap, SQL, SQLite, ActiveRecord, Sqlite3, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Git, Heroku, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign.

Other Skills

Agile Project Management, Kanban, Visual Studio, TDD/BDD, RSPEC, GitHub, Travis CLI, Docker, MVC, Bower, OOP, Atom, Dependency Injection, Microsoft Office, Slack, Trello, Pivotal Tracker, AWS EC2

Language

English, French

PROJECTS =

Academy Panel, Ruby on Rails

(https://patadminpanel.herokuapp.com)

- A user-friendly database panel that can effectively manage students, courses, and instructors.
- Dynamic and intuitive interface built using Bootstrap Admin templates/ Javascript and CSS.
- Technologies include Ruby on Rails, UI Branding, Data Integrity, AJAX in Rails, APIs and deploying a Rails application to

Passion Project - Charity Auction Ruby on Rails

(https:bidsocial.herokuapp.com)

- A Charity Auction website that is dynamic and intuitive built using Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, and CSS
- Created and sourced seeded data to create my own API and RESTful interface for auction items.
- Utilizes algorithms for bidding and countdown timer for each organization's charity auction items.

EDUCATION=

Woz U

Phoenix, AZ

Full stack JAVA program

Sept 2018 - Apr 2019

A part-time 33 weeks boot camp, with an emphasis on Full-Stack JAVA Development with multiple languages and frameworks.

New York Code and Design Academy

Full stack Ruby on Rails program

New York, N.Y.

Oct 2018 - Feb 2019

• Completed a 13 week Software Engineering Intensive program and created dynamic web applications using a variety of platforms, frameworks, and languages including: Ruby, Sinatra, Ruby on Rails

St. John's University

Bachelor of Science in Pharmacy

Queens, N.Y.

Sep 1986 - Jan 1992

• Completed and earned a degree in Pharmacy and was licensed as a Pharmacist in New York State and Florida.

= EXPERIENCE =

Position

eDiagnostic, LLC

Junior Software Engineer

New York, N.Y.

Aug 2018 – Present

Provide strategic vision and product roadmaps for this start-up company's software platform to be utilized by health plans, health systems, and retail channels.

Costco

Rego Park, N.Y.

Pharmacy Intern June 2017 – Jul 2018

 Advise customers on the selection of medication brands, medical equipment and health-care supplies and ran store management by greeting customer, transaction, inventory control, and supply management

Consistently worked in fast paced environment with continuous wave of customers coming to store

Alliance for Positive Health

Plattsburg, N.Y

Independent Contractor HIV/AIDS/STD/HCV Peer Educator

Feb 2012-Apr 2017

- Met with executive members of the Department of Corrections on a bi-weekly basis to negotiate ways in which the needs of the offender population may be met.
- Prepared and submitted monthly course outlines on how best to address the needs and concerns of offenders.